goodcholesterolcount.com 2016-10-11

# Privacy Policy : Good Cholesterol Count

Browse >

[Home](http://goodcholesterolcount.com/ "Browse to: Home") / Privacy Policy 

Thank you for visiting Good Cholesterol Count and for taking interest in our Privacy Policy. We have built this site with the objective of making it a valuable resource for you, and understand the importance of your privacy. We’re very aware of the need to respect, and protect the privacy of all our readers. We attempt to honor or exceed the legal requirements for medical/health information privacy for the state of New York, and the United States of America in general.

Please read this Policy carefully. If you have any questions about this Policy or our data collection, use or disclosure practices, please contact us in any of the ways listed at the end of this Policy.

**What information do we collect?**

Since Good Cholesterol Count’s purpose is to provide you with detailed health care information, we may request correspondingly detailed personal health information. Certain information that we request is necessary for us to provide one or more Good Cholesterol Count services to you. Other information is optional. However, if you elect not to provide this optional information, this choice may limit the value of the Good Cholesterol Count experience for you. For example, if we do not have your children’s ages, we will not be able to provide information about their developmental stages or suggestions for age appropriate games and activities. As you can see, the more information we have about you, the more valuable the Good Cholesterol Count experience can be for you.

Good Cholesterol Count may collect or track the e-mail addresses of visitors that communicate with the Site via e-mail and information knowingly provided by the visitor in online registration forms, information requests, the “Contact Us” section of the Site, and other online resources. We collect personal information through our registration form and also from registration information you provide to our marketing partners (for users that join Good Cholesterol Count though one of our partners). Information collected at registration includes, but is not limited to, name, address, email address, gender and birth date. You may choose to provide additional information, including (but not limited to) such health and lifestyle information about you and your family as marital status and household information (spouse, children, pets, etc.); ethnicity; education; income; occupation; purchasing habits; reading habits; insurance; height; weight; physical and mental health conditions and diseases; symptoms; treatments; medications; medical devices; vitamins; health habits; and participation in research surveys and clinical trials. Generally, in addition to the other uses and features described in this Privacy Policy, we use this information to improve your Good Cholesterol Count experience by tailoring the content displayed in your version of the Site to the information that we describe in this paragraph.

In addition, we might receive information about you from outside sources and add it to your Good Cholesterol Count membership information. We do this to improve personalization of our services (for example, providing better newsletter content, advertising or special offers that we think will interest you). We also may compare our customer list to lists received from other companies, in an effort to avoid sending identical messages to our members.

Even if you do not register with Good Cholesterol Count, we collect or track non-personal information including (1) the home server domain names, e-mail addresses, type of client computer, files downloaded, search engine used, operating system, and type of Web browser of visitors to the Site, and (2) aggregate and user-specific information regarding which pages Site visitors access, using tracking technologies, such as action tags or cookies.

**Cookies**

We and our advertisers collect anonymous information about your use of our site through cookies. Good Cholesterol Count may place “cookies” on your hard drive. The cookie does not tell us who you are. Only you can tell us that. Internet cookies are small text files that save data about individual visitors, save your password so you don’t have to re-enter it each time you visit the Web Site, and help us to deliver personalized content and other services. Many Web browsers are automatically set to accept cookies. You may change your browser settings to either reject cookies or notify you when a cookie is about to be placed on your computer. Please note, however, that rejecting cookies while visiting the Web Site may result in certain parts of the Web Site not operating correctly or as efficiently as if they were allowed. For example, if you are a Good Cholesterol Count member, you may need to enter your username and password each time you visit the Web Site.

The information collected by cookies helps us generate customized content, and also allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our site and for what purpose. For contests or sweepstakes, we may use cookies in order to track your progress and the number of entries in some promotions. For polls, we may use cookies to help ensure that an individual can’t vote more than once on a particular question or issue. We do not store any identifying information in any cookies on your computer.

**Third-Party Advertising**

Our Web advertising partners, such as DoubleClick, may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser in order to control the sequence of advertisements you see and to make sure you don’t see the same ad too many times. DoubleClick does not use information collected via these cookies in its advertising network. To turn off DoubleClick cookies, please visit the DoubleClick website. If you opt out of DoubleClick cookies, you will still see advertisements on our site. These ads will be targeted only on the basis of the non-personal information that is automatically transmitted on the Internet, such as information collected in our Web logs and the approximate geographic location of your computer.

We also have agreements with companies, sometimes called “Ad Networks,” that serve advertising on behalf of third parties. These Ad Networks may place or recognize a unique cookie, sometimes called a “third party cookie,” on your browser. Ad Networks use cookies to understand Web usage patterns of people who see advertisements, to control the sequence of advertisements you see, to provide you with the most relevant advertising, and to make sure you don’t see the same ad too many times. Ad Networks may connect information about pages you visited on our site with information about pages you visit on other sites and show you advertising based on this combined information. While we do not control Ad Networks or what they do with the information they collect, we have relationships only with organizations that have agreed to participate in the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) and abide by NAI principles, which prohibit members from connecting personally identifiable information to information they collect through cookies without your explicit consent.

If you wish to opt out of participating in advertising programs conducted by DoubleClick or Ad Networks, please go to the NAI Opt-Out site and follow the instructions on that site. After you opt out, you will still see advertising on our site, but this advertising will not be tailored to your Web preferences and usage patterns. Please see our Advertising policy for more information about our relationship with advertisers.

Your browser software can be set to reject all cookies or to accept cookies only from our site. Most browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to reject cookies in the “Help” section of the toolbar. If you reject our cookies, you may not be able to log in or use certain functions and conveniences of our site.

In some instances we may include certain links in our e-mails that will allow us to monitor whether you access specific content or advertisements contained in that e-mail. When you click on one of these links, we will record that click and certain activities on the Web page associated with that link. We may use this information for various purposes, such as to conduct internal research on our users’ demographics, interests, and behavior in and to our e-mail advertisements and content. We also use it to customize the content displayed on your version of Good Cholesterol Count, tailoring it to your interests.

**Search**

When you search on our site, we store the search terms and the site(s) visited so that we can continuously improve the quality of our search results.

Giveaways and Contests

We may conduct giveaways, contests and other promotions on the Good Cholesterol Count Web Site in which we may ask you for additional information. We use and treat this information in accordance with the terms of this Policy. Participation in such giveaways and contents is not necessary to use Good Cholesterol Count, and you may choose whether you wish to participate in any particular give-away or contest.

We periodically prepare analyses and reports reflecting visitor and member use of the Good Cholesterol Count Web Site and Good Cholesterol Count services for our internal use as well as for a limited number of our business partners. These reports include aggregate information about Good Cholesterol Count members, and in certain instances, visitors to the Good Cholesterol Count Web Site. The information in these reports will not identify you individually. Our business partners who have access to these reports will not be able to contact you from the information contained in the reports.

**Referral Program**

As part of our referral program, you can provide contact information (such as name and e-mail address) of your friends and family whom you think would like to receive Good Cholesterol Count e-mails and use the Good Cholesterol Count services. The users referred to us receive sample Good Cholesterol Count e-mails, but do not become members until they confirm their interest in the service.

**Market Research**

You may choose to participate in market research activities through Good Cholesterol Count, including health panels and surveys. When participating in such activities, we may ask you to submit personal information. We may combine the personal information you provide to us with research tools and information from other sources, including prescription information. We use this information to perform research, and to prepare reports and analyses for our clients. Our reports and analyses to clients are made only on an anonymous basis.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

**Notice Regarding Online Behavioral Advertising**  
We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our Web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

Good Cholesterol Count reserves the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, update, change, modify or revise this Privacy Policy or our services simply by posting such change, update or modification on the Web Site. Any such addition, update, change, modification or revision will be effective immediately upon posting on the Web Site. Upon any change to this Privacy Policy or our services, we may also notify you via e-mail.

If you do not accept the terms of this Policy, we ask that you do not visit or register with Good Cholesterol Count.

Please [Contact Us](http://goodcholesterolcount.com/about-us/contact/) if you have any further questions.
